Nicholas Fehlberg



me@nicholasfehlberg.com





0455357020



https://nicholasfehlberg.com/

Summary

I'm a full stack web developer and project manager with experience in online marketing, ecommerce and lead generation. I have experience building APIs with Model View Controller frameworks, with two of my recent projects using Ruby On Rails. I've been working online since 2003 and developing sites since 2007. Here are some technical areas in which I have knowledge and proficiency:

Tech Stack:

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

Javascript

Ruby

Rails

Java

PHP

PostgreSQL

Wordpress

Magento

Salesforce

SugarCRM

SpotHub

Shopify

Tools:

Postman

Balsamiq

VS Code

Git

Github

Photoshop

Lightroom

GIMP

My side interests extend to learning new programming languages and tools, and digital ledger technology.

- * Project Manager / CTO ScentByMe perfume company drop shipping, designed web, marketing, catalog assets (New York)
- * CTO Black Dog Books project manager. built out an ecommerce recurring billing admin app + web and print assets (New York)
- * Lead generation platform for New York attorneys (New York)

- * Consulted to companies selling goods and services online (Las Vegas)
- * Marketing Manager of tech wholesale/retailer Lapy King. Built out and managed ecommerce + advertising + print. \$3M in sales (Sydney)
- * Manager of iWhiz CPA Network (Sydney / Chicago)
- * Business Development Manager at Online Marketing Services Agency Magic Jupiter (Sydney)
- * Email and Landing page Design & Testing, Analytics (Sydney)

Github: https://github.com/glenfish

Experience



Freelance Developer

Various Companies
Mar 2021 - Present (1 month +)

Student

LaTrobe University
Apr 2020 - Present (1 year +)

Frontend Web Developer

Various Companies
Jan 2007 - Present (14 years 3 months +)

HC Owner Operator

Various Companies
Jan 2015 - Nov 2019 (4 years 11 months)

Oil & Gas

Halliburton Feb 2014 - Dec 2014 (11 months)

Transporter

Conway Transportation Services Oct 2012 - Jan 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Frontend Web Developer

Freelance Web Development
Sep 2011 - Sep 2012 (1 year 1 month)
Web development, lead generation, ecommerce

Marketing Manager

Jan 2010 - Sep 2011 (1 year 9 months)

Computer hardware sales (online and retail). Website development and online media buying.

Chief Executive Officer

Black Marketing Inc

Feb 2007 - Dec 2009 (2 years 11 months)

Digital marketing services agency

Digital Marketing Manager

iMega

Feb 2003 - Jan 2007 (4 years)

Agency manager, media buyer, business development

Audio Engineer

Glasshouse Studios

Jan 1999 - Jan 2003 (4 years 1 month)

Recording demos, singles, EPs and albums for various musical artists. Audio and video production work.

Audio Engineer

Various Companies

Mar 1994 - Mar 1999 (5 years 1 month)

Worked studio sessions for commercial TV ads

Assistant Audio Engineer

Song Zu Sydney and Singapore

Dec 1989 - Feb 1994 (4 years 3 months)

Education



Coder Academy

2020 - 2021

La Trobe University

Bachelor of Applied Information Technology, Computer Programming 2020 - 2023

University of Technology Sydney

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering 1996 - 1997

Bankstown Grammar

High School Diploma 1987 - 1989

Licenses & Certifications

- in HTML Essential Training LinkedIn
- in Introduction to CSS LinkedIn
- in CSS Essential Training LinkedIn
- Cybersecurity Awareness: Phishing and Whaling LinkedIn
- in JavaScript Essential Training LinkedIn
- CSS Layouts: From Float to Flexbox and Grid LinkedIn
- Tim Workflow Tools for Web Developers LinkedIn
- in Git Essential Training: The Basics LinkedIn
- Computer Components and Peripherals for IT Technicians LinkedIn
- Blockchain: Beyond the Basics LinkedIn
- in WordPress: Creating an Intranet Website LinkedIn
- Google Technical Support Certification Google LPLJKQY8BTPL

Skills

Online Marketing • Web Development • Front-end Development • Web Design • Digital Marketing • E-commerce • Advertising • Design • Marketing • HTML